Guide to the Natalie L. M. Petesch Papers, 1940-2006 SC.2006.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Offprints and Clippings of Petesch's Writings, 1964-1998; VI.
  - "How Cupro Azenfant Destroyed the U.S. Mint" and "Dancing" in New Letters 46.4, Summer 1980 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - "A Journal for the New Year" in The Georgia Review 34.2, Summer 1980 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - "Buell's Big Bet" in Kansas Quarterly 12.3, Summer 1980 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - "I, Constanza" in Wittenberg Review of Literature and Art, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Review of David Ray's Tramp's Cup and Enough of Flying in The Greenfield Review 9.1/2, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - "The University Interviews Felix Mateo, Class of '85" in The Akros Review 4, Spring 1981 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Interview with W.D. Ehrhart in The Greenfield Review 10.1/2, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - "The Street" in Snapdragon 5.2, Spring 1982 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Fiction Competition Judged in Kansas Quarterly 14.1, Winter 1982 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Review of Duncan's Colony and Soul Clap Its Hands and Sin g in New Letters 50.1, Fall 1983 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - "Main Street Morning" in New Letters Reader I, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - "Love" in California Quarterly 23/24, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - "A Man Called Manuel" in Crazyhorse 27, Fall 1984 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - "Through a Glass, Darkly" in The Chariton Review 11.2, Fall 1985 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - "Love" in Best Short Stories from California Quarterly, 1971-1985, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - "The Man With the Pinto Bean Hair" (Spanish Version) in Discurso Literario 3.2, Spring 1986 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - "Heroes" in Pittsburgh Magazine, July 1987 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - "Manolo's Secret" in New Letters 54.3, Spring 1988 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Review of Sam's Book by David Ray in The Chariton Review 14.1, Spring 1988 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - "Dionisio's Restaurant" in Negative Capability 9.3, 1989 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - "A Village in Eden" in The Chariton Review 15.2, Fall 1989 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Review of The Stain by Fred Viebahn in Prairie Schooner 64.3, Fall 1990 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - "Love in a Time of War" in The Pittsburgh Quarterly 1.2, Spring 1991 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - "Benito in Love" in The Bridge 4.2, Summer/Fall 1994 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - "A Manual for the Corridors" in Artful Dodge 32/33, 1998 (Box 56, Folder 10)
- Multimedia, 1955-1998; VII.
  The multimedia items in this series largely consist of sound recordings of Petesch reading her short stories and occasionally excerpts from her longer works. Some are tapings of public presentations, including radio broadcasts, while others are practice recordings she made privately in preparation for a speech or reading. The fact that she made these practice recordings gives a unique insight into Petesch's approach toward her public life as an author. Most are on audiocassette tapes, with one five-inch magnetic tape reel included among them.
  One box in this series contains microfilm reels that Petesch had made in order to preserve copies of writings she produced during the 1950s. These include papers she wrote for her master's degree at Brandeis University and one of her unpublished novels, though the label indicates that she herself was unsure of the content of this last reel.
  The final item in this series is a small box of lead ore that Petesch brought back as a souvenir from Kellogg, Idaho when she was researching her novel Duncan's Colony. This unique piece of realia is housed in its own box in order to protect the rest of the collection from particulate damage.
  - Documents Accompanying Audio Recordings (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Tape of Interview at the University of Iowa After Winning the Award for Short Fiction (content not confirmed), 1974 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts Done at Brandeis University for the M.A., 1955-1956 (Box 58, Reel 1)
  - Two Masters Papers from Brandeis University, 1955-1956 (Box 58, Reel 2)
  - Copy of either Writ in Remembrance or Tree Without Wings, 1957 (Box 58, Reel 3)
  - Interview with Patricia Schweitzer and Natalie L.M. Petesch, May 16, 1977 (Box 59, Cassette 1)
  - Reading of "Main Street Morning" (side A) and "The Man with the Pinto Bean Hair", November 1977 (Box 59, Cassette 2)
  - Readings from The Last Chronicle of Eden, 1977 (Box 59, Cassette 3)
  - Readings of "The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K." (side A) and "Journal for the New Year" (side B) for New Letters on the Air, 1979 (Box 59, Cassette 4)
  - Introductions for Idaho Readings (side A); Odyssey of KK chapter one and "Ku Klux Klan" (side B; taped over) (Box 59, Cassette 5)
  - Introduction and "A Journal for the New Year" (side A) and "I, Constanza" (side B), 1978-1979 (Box 59, Cassette 6)
  - Reading of "A Journal for the New Year (Resolutions, Memos, Whimsies)", November 21, 1977 (Box 59, Cassette 7)
  - Introduction and "The End of the World", November 2, 1978 (Box 59, Cassette 8)
  - Reading of "A Man Called Manuel" (Box 59, Cassette 9)
  - Reading of "The Assassins", January 18, 1976 (Box 59, Cassette 10)
  - Introduction and "Ellie Brume" Reading at Pitt (side A) and "The Grievance Adjustor" Reading at Louisville (side B), 1975 (Box 59, Cassette 11)
  - Reading of "The Life and Letters of Hannah Gordon", October 1, 1984 (Box 59, Cassette 12)
  - Dedication and First Pages of Katinou Kalokovich, Plus Notes to Pennsylvania Library Association (tape damaged), November 1, 1983 (Box 59, Cassette 13)
  - Reading of "Noah Drowns in Air" (side A) and Intro to "Saigon" and "The End of the World" (side B), 1981-1982 (Box 59, Cassette 14)
  - The Polish Americans, WQED, June 9, 1998 (Box 59, Cassette 15)
  - "Journal for the New Year," New Letters (Box 59, Cassette 16)
  - "The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K." with Introduction for Kansas City New Letters, November 9, 1978 (Box 59, Cassette 17)
  - Mother Root Program, Natalie Petesch (Box 59, Cassette 18)
  - "Silences of Salinas" (side A) and "Pillars of Ore"/"Love" (side B), October 1983 (Box 59, Cassette 19)
  - "Two Novels," New Letters (Box 59, Cassette 20)
  - Lead Ore from The Bunker Hill Co., Kellogg, Idaho (Box 60, Item 1)